Hey, everybody. Welcome to
the content video going over
section 7.2 of your textbook,
creating arrays from existing
data. Really, what we're
going to talk about in this
content video is NumPy and
a couple of the basic NumPy
features. So one of the
things that is really, really
beneficial about NumPy is that
it uses C code with Python to,
oh, there's a word for it,
optimize, I think. Yeah, to make
your Python code run faster,
smoother, a little bit better.
So arrays are based more in C
code and they're faster than the
default Python list, but operate
very, very similar to the Python list.
So we're going to talk about how
you can take a Python list and
make it into a NumPy array so that
you can have faster, better code.
So as in, oh, let me type
something here first.
NumPy arrays.
I cancel.
Arrays.
Okay.
So we're going to import NumPy.
A lot of people import NumPy as NP
because it's quicker and faster to
write. Speaking of optimizing, you
know. um so we can do that but it
doesn't super matter so let's make
a list we'll call it homework scores
and let's assign that to
the value of 23.6 48.9 47.2
and 49.8 and we'll do full
points 50 so some people
did really good on the
homework and some people just
have opportunities to learn
so let's convert that so
to do this we simply say we
need to make a new variable to
actually be that numpy array so
we'll maybe call that numpy array
sign that to the value of np.array.
And then you throw in the
list that you want changed. So
let's print out numpy array.
Goodness, sorry guys.
There we go.
Let's print these both
out. Take a look at them.
I don't know why that took so
long it's not helping convince
you guys that numpy is actually
faster so anyways here's our
default python list and here is
our numpy array notice that we
actually don't have any commas
separating the values when we see
our numpy array printed out so
that's a good designation that if
you ever see one in an output
console you know which is which
And that's all I have for this
content video, but there's some
really great sections about
NumPy in this book. We are going
to go over too many more things
about NumPy except for just
arrays, but we will talk about
pandas in a later content video.
So we'll kind of come back to
NumPy and what it can be used
for at a later date. So thanks
for watching this content video.